American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj. 1898-1984 APS.Archives.IIj APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, Nov. 17, 1899; 10x8; United States. Dept. of the Treasury
    Washington, Typed L.S.: H. A. Taylor 1p., end. Requested documents have been sent to the A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, Nov. 20, 1899.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hay [sic, Hays], Nov. 21, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Henkels, S. V. (Stanislaus Vincent), 1854-1926
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns sale of U.S. Geological Survey reports.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, Nov. 21, 1899; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: S[amuel] P[ierpont] Langley 1p. Concerns copy of a National Museum Bulletin wanted by A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, Nov. 24, 1899.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 23, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Haupt, Lewis M. (Lewis Muhlenberg), b. 1844
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns error in separates of his paper on breakwater at Aransas Pass, Texas. Refers to another paper on failures in dams. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 38, pp.135-147. Paper on dams not published.
  - Letter to E[lla M] Morrison [sic, Morison, Nov. 24, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end., and add. Asks to correct H.C. Baird's obituary of A. Biddle. Refers to Pepper Memorial.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Nov. 26, 1899; 8x5-3/4; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends reply of MacCalla & co. about extras of his article. For enclosure, see MacCalla & co. to H. Allen, Nov. 26, 1889.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Nov. 27, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Bache, Richard Meade
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asks about Franklin letter to Mme. Helvetius.
  - Letter to [MacCalla & Co.], Nov. 27, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Philbrick, Francis S. (Francis Samuel), 1876-1970
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end. and add. Asks about A.P.S. publications.
  - Annual report for 1899, Nov. 29, 1899; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., D.S.: Benj[amin] Smith Lyman, J[ames] Cheston Morris 2p., end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) References to numismatics collection, Peale collection of Stone Age Relics, A.P.S. portraits, Isaac Hays.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 1, 1899; 3-1/2X5-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L. on postal card S.: Edw[ard] J. Nolan 1p. and add. Asks if A.P.S. has all parts of Falconer and Cautley, Fauna antiqua Sivalensis, 1846.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 3, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Galloway, M. J.
    Akron, O., A.L.S. 2p. Offers fac simile of Declaration of independence for sale.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 4, 1899; 8x5-1/2; Bonaparte, Roland, prince, 1858-1924
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns A.P.S. exchange of publications with l'Association historique pour l'Etude de l'Afrique du Nord and Le Comité de L'Afrique française.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Dec. 5, 1899; 10x8; United States National Museum
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p., end. Sending copy of Museum Bulletin, as requested, for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 6, 1899; 8x5; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerns nomination of Albert C. Peale for membership. Discusses letter from A. Heilprin.
  - Letter to Boise [sic, Boies] Penrose, Dec. 9, 1899; 10-1/2x8, 2x8-1/2; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Cha[rle]s D[oolittle] Walcott 1p. Enc. Returns memorandum of I.M. Hays concerning Geological Survey Bulletins. With covering letter from Penrose to Hays, Dec. 11, 1899.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Dec. 11, 1899; 9x6; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 1p., end. His paper on descent of Pierids is nearly ready. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 39, pp.4-67.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morrison [sic, Morison], Dec. 11, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Michael, Helen Abbott, 1857-1904
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Returns catalogue and reprint of D.G. Brinton notice.
  - List of medals, medallions &c. in Cabinet of A.P.S. deposited with the Penna. Museum & School of Industrial Art, Dec. 13, 1899; 14x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    D.S.: J[ames] Cheston Morris 4p., end.: Please send proper receipt for above For receipt, see Pennsylvania museum. Receipt No.354...Dec. 13, 1899.
  - List of medals, plaster casts of medals, coins, medallions, etc. deposited by the A.P.S. with the Pennsylvania Museum...under Receipt No. 354 (U.82), Dec. 13, 1899; 13x8; Pennsylvania Museum and School of Industrial Art
    Phila., Typed D. 1p. Two copies. Cf. A.P.S. List of medals...Dec. 13, 1899. For receipt, see Pennsylvania museum. Receipt No.354...Dec. 13, 1899.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1899; 11x8-1/2, 9-1/2x6; Alabama. History Commission
    Typed L.S.: Thomas M[cAdory] Owen 1p., end. Enc. of 4p. printed circular Asks again about Alabama material in A.P.S. library. Asks about estate of D.G. Brinton.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 14, 1899; 9x6 11-1/2x9; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Forwards letter from Otto Harrassowitz, book dealer in Leipzig, asking for E.Y. McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, Dec. 16, 1899; 10x8; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Asks about J.H. Payne's manuscript on the Cherokees, cited in E.G. Squier's Serpent symbol.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, Dec. 16, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. War Dept.
    Washington, Typed L.S.: G[eorge] D[eRue] Meiklejohn 1p. Concerns copy of Gen. Wood's report on the provinces of Cuba, for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, Dec. 23, 1899.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Prime, Dec. 18, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Vice-president.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 19, 1899; 8x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges nomination as Councillor.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Prime, Dec. 19, 1899; 8x5; Trumbull, H. Clay (Henry Clay), 1830-1903
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 20, 1899; 8x5-1/2, 9-1/2x6; Hoyt, John Wesley, 1831-1912
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. of 2p. printed sheet Asks about A.P.S. history. Encloses proposal for National University.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 21, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Cannot attend Library Committee meeting.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 21, 1899; 10x8; Library of Congress. Manuscript Division
    Washington, A.L.S.: Herbert Friedenwald 1p. Concerns Library of Congress copies of Declaration of Independence broadside. Refers to Roberdeau Buchanan.
  - Letter to Frederick Prime, Dec. 23, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Sadtler, Samuel P. (Samuel Philip), 1847-1923
  - Letter to Frederick Prime, Dec. 23, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Vaux, George
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Will serve as Clerk of Annual Election.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 26, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. A.E. Brown declines appointment as Councillor.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 27, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Cruice, Mary Z.
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 2p. Concerns searching done for library. Refers to John Thomson.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Prime, Dec. 27, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
    Upper Darby, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges nomination as Councillor.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Dec. 29, 1899; 10.1/2x8; North Carolina. Council
    Raleigh, Typed L.S.: Baylus Cade, Private secretary 1p. Concerns A.P.S. request for set of North Carolina Colonial and State records.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec., 1899; 8x5; Mallet, John William
    Charlottesville, Va., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends payment for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, 1899; 6-1/2x5; DaCosta, Jacob Mandes, 1833-1900
    [Phila.,] A.L.S. 1p. Send invitation to Conversazione to Eugene von Rosen.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Phila., L. 2p. Concerns W.V. McKean and Phillips prize essays.
  - Letter to Irving E. Campbell, 1899; 11x8-1/2; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    [Phila., ] Draft 1p. Concerns Campbell's inquiry about Phillips prize essay. Written on same sheet as Campbell to A.P.S., Jan 14, 1899.
  - Resolution of approval for plans for restoration of Independence Hall and Square, 1899; 5x8; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    []. Copy. 2p. In hand of I.M.Hays.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], 1898?; 6-1/4x4-1/4; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    A.L.S. 1p. Offers list of nominations for officers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, 1898?; 8x5; Institution of Mechanical Engineers (Great Britain)
    London, Printed L. 1p. Change of address.
  - Invitation to A.P.S. to attend 50th anniversary of founding of Observatory, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Imperatorskai︠a︡ akademīi︠a︡ nauk i khudozhestv (Russia)
    Printed D. filled in in MS. 1p.
  - Letter to [James] Cheston Morris, Jan. 23, 1900; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Henry S[mith] Pritchett 1p. Asks about Mason and Dixon surveying instruments in A.P.S. collections.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Feb. 3, 1900; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Henry S[mith] Pritchett 1p. Concerns Mason and Dixon surveying instruments, Rittenhouse transit.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Philadelphia, Feb. 21, 1900; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Henry S. Prickett. 3p. Concerning maps in the APS dealing with the Pennsylvania-Maryland boundary, especially an early map based on the Mason-Dixon survey.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Philadelphia, Aug. 16, 1900; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Andrew Braid. 1p. Concerning the APS copy of James Logan "Claims of the proprietors..." (see: 974.8:L82c)
  - Annual report for 1900, Dec. 7, 1900; 10x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., D.S.: J[ames] Cheston Morris, Benj[amin] Smith Lyman 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns collections and portraits.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 17, 1900; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. Orders Proceedings, containing views of the Hall.
  - Letter to I. Minis Hays, Oct. 14, 1901; 11x8-1/2 and 5-1/2x7-1/4; Konkle, Burton Alva, 1861-1944
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and enc.of note by James T. Mitchell, Oct. 7, 1901. Concerning photograph of George Bryan.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 21, 1901; 9x5-1/2; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning Antonio Perez manuscript in the Library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 22, 1901; 9x5-1/2; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Identifies Antonio Perez.
  - Annual report for 1901, Dec. 6, 1901; 10x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., D.S.: J[ames] Cheston Morris, Benj[amin] Smith Lyman 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns collections and portraits. List of donations is complete through 1900. Cf. Proceedings, v.40, pp.165-166.
  - Letter to J[ames] E. Creighton, President, American Philosophical Association, New York, April 7, 1902; 10-1/2x8; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 1p. Copy. Concerning the necessity of changing the name of the American philosophical association.
  - Letter to I[saac] J[ones] Wistar, President, Amer.Philos.Assn.[sic], April 9, 1902; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Creighton, James Edwin, 1861-1924
    Ithaca,N. Y., A.L.S. 4p. Concerning the selection of the name for the American philosophical association
  - Letter to I[saac] J. Wistar, Philadelphia, April 10, 1902; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Gardiner, H. Norman (Harry Norman), 1855-1927
    Northampton, Mass., Typed L.S.: H.N.Gardiner, Secretary, Am. Philos.Assn. 1p. Concerning the selection of the name, American philosophical association.
  - Letter to J[ames] E. Creighton, Ithaca, N.Y., April 10, 1902; 10-1/2x8; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
  - Letter to H[arry] N. Gardiner, Sec'y of the American philosophical association, Northampton, Mass., April 12, 1902; 10-1/2x8; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 1p. "Copy" Concerning the necessity for changing the name of the American philosophical association.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the American philosophical society, April 14, 1902; 5-1/2x7-3/4; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the correspondence pertaining to the necessity of changing the name of the American philosophical association.
  - Letter to Mrs. Alfred [Mary T. E.] Paschall, Aug. 29, 1902; 8x5; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Suggests she send request to photograph horologium to I.M. Hays.
  - Letter to [Charles Leander] Doolittle, Sept. 2, 1902; 9x6; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends request from Mary Paschall about photographing Horologium. For enclosure, see M. Paschall to I.M. Hays, [1902]
  - Letter to the Curators of the A.P.S., Oct. 24, 1902; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators. Davis, W. W. H. (William Watts Hart), 1820-1910
    Doylestown, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Asks permission to photograph model of John Fitch's steamboat.
  - Letter to the Curators of the A.P.S., Oct. 24, 1902; 10-1/2x8; Davis, W. W. H. (William Watts Hart), 1820-1910
  - Letter to H. N. Gardener, Secretary of the American Philosophical Association, Northampton, Mass., Dec. 1, 1902; 10-1/4x8; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 1p. "Copy" Concerning the necessity to change the name of the American philosophical association.
  - Letter to I[saac] J. Wistar, President of the APS, Dec. 2, 1902; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Gardiner, H. Norman (Harry Norman), 1855-1927
    Northampton, Mass., Typed L.S.: H.N.Gardiner, Secretary of the American philosophical association. 1p.and end. Concerning the necessity to change the name of the American philosophical association.
  - Letter to I[saac] J. Wistar, President of the APS, Philadelphia, Dec. 8, 1902; 10-3/4x8-1/2, 3-3/4x5-1/2; Gardiner, H. Norman (Harry Norman), 1855-1927
    Northampton, Mass., Typed L.S.: H. N.Gardiner, Sec., American Philosophical Association. 1p.and note (in pencil) from Wistar to Hays; Dec. 11, 1902. Concerning the necessity to change the name of the American philosophical association.
  - Letter to W. Hugh Spottiswoode, Feb. 25, 1903; 10-1/2x8; United States. Patent Office
    Washington, Typed copy 1p. Franklin printing press given by John B. Murray to Museum of National Institute in 1842. Now in National Museum.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Feb. 27, 1903; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Spottiswoode, W. Hugh
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. Forwards letter from U.S. Patent Office about location of Franklin's printing press. For enclosure, see U.S. Patent office to W.H. Spottiswoode, Feb. 25, 1903.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1903; 8x5-1/2; Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
    Upper Darby, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end.: Report of Curators presented May 1, 1903 Enc. wanting Forwards request for photograph from H.S. Blanchard & Co.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, April 22, 1903; 7x4-1/2; Fould, Mme Wilhelmine Joséphine Simonin, 1836-; Gustave Haller
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. Presents her publication on French painters and comments on it. For publication, see: 920:F82.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, April 22, 1903; 7x4-1/2; Haller, Gustav
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. Forwards his publication: Nos Grandes Peintres. Tipped in: Haller,G. Nos Grandes peintres (920:H14).
  - Letter to Dr. [James McKeen] Cattell, Dec. 12, 1903; 11x8-1/2; Smith, Edgar Fahs, 1854-1928
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. Concerning the necessity of changing the name of the American philosophical association.
  - Letter to Josiah Royce, Cambridge, Mass., Dec. 12, 1903; 11x8-1/2; Smith, Edgar Fahs, 1854-1928
  - Annual report for 1905, Dec. 1, 1905; 8-1/2x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., D.S.: C[harles] L[eander] Doolittle 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns work done on portraits and busts.
  - Transmutation of the elements., Nov., 1906; 13x8; "Cursum Perficio"
    The transformation of silver into gold... Typed D.S. 6p. and end. Offered for Magellanic premium.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Nov. 30, Dec. 1, 1906; 8x5; Harjes, John H.
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p.and add.describing the cane. Describes the cane of B.Franklin, given to him by Edward M. Robinson. Leaves it to the APS. Description printed: Smyth, VI,156. Cane is in Philosophical Hall. Accession number 58-48.
  - Letter to Dr. [Joshua L.] Barton, Feb. 7, 1906; 6x4-3/4; Kimber, M. S.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. History of picture of Benjamin Franklin, a gift to Dr. Barton.
  - Address read at Franklin BiCentenary, April 18, 1906; 13x8; Keighley, Fred C.
    Philadelphia, D.S. 5p.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1906; 10-3/4x8; Keighley, Fred C.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks A.P.S. for inviting him to participate in Franklin Bi-centenary.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] M. S. K[imber], April 26, 1906; 8x5; Kimber, Albert W. (Albert William), b. 1878
    A.L.S. with initials. 2p. Recollections of [Catherine Wister] Bache.
  - Letter to J[oseph] G[eorge] Rosengarten, Philadelphia, April 27, 1906; 10x8; Biesel, Augustus
    Paris, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. Encloses two photographs of the Franklin house in Passy. Hopes the APS will use them.
  - Letter to J[oseph] G[eorge] Rosengarten, Philadelphia, May 22, 1906; 10x8; Biesel, Augustus
    Paris, Typed L.S. 4p. Enc. Concerning the sale of a Greuze portrait of Franklin. Concerning a copy of the table on which the treaty of alliance was signed. Refers to Smyth and the APS. Encloses pictures of the portrait and the table.
  - Letter to J[oseph] G[eorge] Rosengarten, Philadelphia, June 5, 1906; 10-1/2x8; Smith, J. Somers, jr.
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. C.H.Hart asserts the portrait is not by Greuze. Would like to know the price the Greuze Franklin portrait did bring.
  - Letter to the [American Philosophical Society], Nov. 19, 1906; 11x8-1/2; Robinson, John
    Salem, Mass., Typed L.S. 1p. Sends photographs of Mugford's rudder and a painting of his ship,in Peabody Museum. Wants copy of Magellanic premium. See print collection for the photographs.
  - Concerning Franklin's being present at the dedicatory services of Franklin college, Dec. 7, 1906; 11x8-1/2; Diffenderffer, Frank Ried, 1833-1921
    Lancaster, Typed D. 2p. Copy. Enc. with note from A.H.Hershey to I.M.Hays; Dec. 8, 1906.
  - Note to I[saac] Minis Hays, Philadelphia, Dec. 8, 1906; 5-1/4x8-1/2; Hershey, Andrew Hiestand, 1852-
    Lancaster, Typed N.S. 1p. Enc. Encloses article by Diffenderffer concerning Franklin.
  - Speech to the American philosophical society from the Göttingen Akademie der wissenschaften at the 1906 Franklin celebration, 8x6-1/2; Wiechert, Emil, b. 1861
    D.S. 8p. In German. with English translation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 1/13, 1907; 11x9; Société impériale des amis des sciences, d'anthropologie et d'ethnographie
    L.S.: Stschelkanovzeff. 2p. In French. Concerning lacunea in the APS holdings of their publications.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Jan. 10, 1907; 11x8-1/2, 14-1/2x11-1/4; Societas Regia Scientiarum Upsaliensis
    Upsala, Printed L.and typed L. 8p. 200th anniversary of Carolus Linnaeus.
  - Letter to the president of the American Philosophical Society, Jan., 1907; 15x11-1/4; University of Aberdeen
    Printed L.S.: J. Marshall Lang. 2p. Thanks for address on the quartercentenary of the University.
  - Letter to Edgar F[ahs] Smith, March 23, 1907; 11x8-1/2; Thomas Jefferson Memorial Association of the United States
    Washington, Typed L.S. W[illia]m Shields McKean 1p., end.: Report of Curators presented May 3, 1907 Asks loan of Jefferson material for Jamestown Exposition.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minus [sic, Minis] Hays, April 3, 1907; 11x8; Wilson, William P. (William Powell), 1844-1927
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end.: Report of the Curators present[ed] May 17, 1907 Enc. Returns list of material wanted for Jamestown Exposition. Does not approve of loaning museum materials at any time. Will attend 50th anniversary of Michigan Agricultural College as A.P.S. representative.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 4, 1907; 9x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., A.L.S. C[harles] L[eander] Doolittle 1p. Enc. Encloses request for Jefferson matrial for Jameston Exposition. Curators do not approve. For enclosure, see Thomas Jefferson memorial association of U.S. to Edgar F[ahs] Smith, March 23, 1907.
  - Response to toast to the "Memory of Franklin"..., April 20, 1907; 8" x 13"; Sulzberger, Mayer, 1843-1923
    Typed D. 4 leaves. Given at Annual dinner of the American philosophical society.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 5, 1907; 9x6-1/2; Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns copy of Franklin chair. Refers to W.P. Wilson, death of A.H. Smyth. Cannot approve loan of material of Jamestown Exposition, although he would like to oblige M.D. Learned.
  - Letter to W[illiam] H[enry] Holmes, Washington, May 22, 1907; 10-1/2x8; Thomas, Cyrus, 1825-1910
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p.,end.by W.H.Holmes. Concerning the manuscript: Uae rugotzlem (497.4:Ua15), in the Library, in Cakchikel.
  - Letter to Miss Christine S. Trepp, Philadelphia, May 25, 1907; 10-1/2x8; Holmes, William Henry, 1846-1933
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Answers question pertaining to the Cakchikel language manuscript in the Library: Uae rugotzlem.. (497.4:Ua15), as Dr. Cyrus Thomas answered the question.
  - Letter to C[hristine] S. Trepp, Philadelphia, May 21, 1908; 11-3/4x8; Hispanic Society of America
    New York, Typed L.S.: W.H.Gates. 1p.and add. Explains the aims of the Society.
  - Annual report for 1909, Dec. 3, 1909; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller, C[harles] L[eander] Doolittle 2p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Franklin, Washington and Jefferson portraits glazed at suggestion and expense of John T. Morris. Priestley portrait repaired.
  - Letter to Joshua L. Barton, March 2, 1910; 6-3/4x4-1/4; Laws, Bertha M.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Secretary for Agnes Irwin refers Dr. Barton to Russell Duane for information.
  - Letter to Joshua L. Barton, March 22, 1910; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Duane, Russell, 1866-
    Typed L.S. 1p. Concerning minature presented to Benjamin Franklin by Louis XVI.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 26, 1910; 8x5-1/2; Société des antiquaires de la Morinie
    St. Omer, L.S.: Charles Legrand. 2p. In French. Cannot furnish publications wanted by the APS.
  - [Report of the special committee on site for a new hall], February 10, 1911; 8 1/2" x 11"; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: Charlemagne Tower, chairman, John T. Morris, I. Minis Hays, John F. Lewis (?), W. W. Keen. 8 leaves.
  - Letter to I. Minis Hays, secretary of A.P.S., Feb. 21, 1911; 8 1/2" x 11"; Cope & Stewardson
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 3 leaves. Report of architects upon Society's hall.